2020 it's 12:03PM.
Present is myself, Eric Anderson,
Kurt Dowling,
Diane is here,
Daryl is here, and Kathy Palazzi is here.
So
absent is Carol Lee and Ed Kasich.
So item number two COVID-nineteen
response.
So what I really wanted to focus this meeting on
is just what each of the individual groups are doing
in terms of COVID-nineteen
and
what things we need to start considering as we begin to open up town hall and open up
you know
for that both. So what I'd like to do is start maybe with
Kurt and do the fire commission first
and then we'll do library then we'll do senior transportation then we'll do Daryl and then I'll talk a little bit about town hall and we'll go from there.
Kurt?
>> Okay, first off, I'll be talking also for the fire department
as I am Chief Mike's representative.
I keep thanking him for that.
We're still following the guidelines set up originally as far as the facility goes here at the firehouse.
No
crowds,
no meetings,
everything's being held
virtual or like you'll have an officer's meeting, but there'll be
six feet apart
out in the bays
basically
with their masks on going
over things. Our crews are
still responding with full PPE.
We're still,
the ambulance as before is still very busy.
We're starting to pick up on some of our regular work,
I. E. The drug overdoses,
the psyche valves, things like that,
non COVID
responses, but everything
remains the same as far as
any meetings or anything like that goes. Now, my question to you is,
did you
or the Board of Selectmen set up a timeline to
start the phase in, say occupancy of the buildings back in
or
you know, what, what I need to let,
let Ronnie know. We have a fire commission meeting tonight,
virtual.
So
I can, I can bring it up there if there is any pertinent information?
>> So the,
so so to answer that question at the last board of selectman meeting,
the board put off any discussion of reopening
town buildings until
this coming meeting. So I don't have any guidance for you specifically on that.
It will be a discussion by the Board of Selectmen on the eighth. Okay.
>> All right. And like I said, right now, I did
talk to Mindy.
Right now they're still planning on having our,
which is our largest fundraiser of the year is
the steak supper in September.
So they'll
have to follow all the guidelines at that time if we do go through with it. But just to let you know, it hasn't been canceled yet.
And that's up
to the board of directors and the president.
Sure.
Okay.
>> Then like I said, I'll wait for the eighth and see what the which way the board of selector are going before
I, before I tell Wally or Ronnie anything.
>> Okay. And remember,
because the fire department is a critical
it was never completely shut down,
you know, per the governor's orders. It was just, you know, the same thing, social distancing rules apply,
disinfectant protocols apply,
you know.
>> We
practice that from the, from the go.
Just the fact that the
facility itself, you know, closed.
It's not, it's not closed to the membership because we still have the respondent clause.
Just that it's closed for like our
monthly meetings, things like that, you know, public of course. Sure.
And just to make a note,
>> Ron's in the process of putting together the
UTV purchase
for the and trailer.
We'll be
coming to you shortly once that gets set. Also, we
had our final,
virtual,
final inspection on a tanker, and a tanker should be arriving in the state sometime either by the end of the week or first part of next week.
And with, hopefully a July 1, in service date.
Okay.
>> That's all. I got the report. Thank you Kurt. Diane, library?
>> Yes. Hi, I just wanted to jump in. Am I taking the minutes?
>> No. Mean
I would assume it's Diane.
So
Carol can read it off and take the minutes when she gets a chance. That's her penance for missing the meeting. Okay. I just was double checking to make sure. I'm happy to, but Carol it's Carol's role. Right? Correct.
>> Okay.
Perfect
Sorry
No problem.
The library presented a four page,
reopening plan to the board of selectmen at their last meeting
And I guess they they thought it was a good report
The question from the library is does this plan need to be actually approved by somebody, Board of Selectman, Eastern Highland before proceeding with it?
>> So Eastern Highlands,
no.
As a courtesy I sent a copy to Rob Miller of Eastern Highlands.
He didn't have any real issues with it.
You know I
explained
to Amy that I thought it was a reasonable plan and that as far as I was concerned, she was fine with going to the curbside pickup.
But that, you know, and as soon as we started,
you know actually opening up buildings we could proceed with
that
but that has not occurred yet.
>> As you know the library has been closed to the public since March 16.
It had it reopened
on Monday
for curbside pickup.
Correct.
So Amy's been there. Of course, she was in the building a half hour before she lost power for several hours. So that was fun.
The library,
the curbside pickup is now
Mondays.
Let's see.
Monday and Wednesday, ten to four and Tuesday and Thursday,
one to seven.
Again, the library the building itself is not open to the public.
All books being returned to the
book drop
are being quarantined for seventeen hour twenty try to remember again. Seventy two hours before being reshelved
and logged back in.
All programs are being done via Zoom and meetings.
They had a reptile
program
that had about 50 people in attendance, which was pretty good. They like that.
Discussions
are being held via Zoom.
And kids story hours are being held once or twice a day, Monday through Friday.
So they're still doing those kinds of things.
The library
board of directors and librarian are in the process
of acquiring things like plexiglass,
Clorox wipes,
hand sanitizers,
disinfected products, paper towels, soaps, gloves and those sort of things for when they actually do reopen.
When they do reopen, the bathroom will probably be off limits for a while.
We have noticed that the cleaning people have not been in for quite some time.
The question is, are they doing the town office building?
>> Yes.
So
has Amy spoke with them? Because I gave Amy the contact information for the cleaning people to deal with them directly.
>> Right. She's gonna be Well, we we talked about it last night. The library board met last night.
That
information and told her to go check because it looks like, again, they haven't been in. And are they doing any kind of disinfecting or are they just doing vacuuming and dusting?
>> They're not really doing any disinfecting
other than the bathrooms.
Okay.
Right.
And that's pretty much it. Anybody have any questions?
Okay.
Kathy, Senior Transportation.
>> Yes.
As you know,
governor Lamont has said
the seniors are still in step three, which he hopes to open on July 20.
And, if so, we're hoping that we can start our senior transportation
activities again.
For the meanwhile,
Ellie Scug will
begin delivering food pantry and food share.
She will be starting tomorrow on June 3, I believe. She has been
shadowing Paul
Bancroft,
and I guess he's told her exactly what to do and so forth. My understanding is that Mickey will be following her tomorrow, and Mickey will be showing her the people that will get the boxes so that it will go very smoothly.
That's the plan, I believe.
Correct. You can let me know if if the plan has changed.
And we have no medicals because doctor's office have, of course, canceled all medicals
at this point, and we expect, hopefully, to start medicals the week of July 20.
And we're hoping that we will be able to start our lunches again on July 24,
but we're actually going going to go slow with that, Eric. We want to wait and see
how we do the week of the twentieth, and we may put the lunches off till the thirty first.
And the plan so far with John is we're going to have people six feet apart and not have all the people sitting in one room as we had done in the past.
We'll be using two rooms.
Okay. That's about that's about all I have unless you, you know, have something
to add.
>> Yeah. I I think it's still way too early to say how that's all gonna play out,
right now. Exactly.
Right.
>> We are, I think, going to have to end because CERT is ending their
Ted's food delivery program.
So we are gonna have to replace that.
And there's at least, there's basically at this point two residents in town that we need to deal with.
Right. Mrs. Barry and Mrs. Duvall
you know in both cases we need to provide some method of getting them food.
So in and I have not talked to Ellie about
this yet. I was planning on it. It's on my list. I just haven't got to it. But the question becomes, do we begin
to start taking just a few people
to the grocery stores
and working
with the protocol from Eastern Highlands Health and
Or do we
you know, and essentially deliver the food to them via Ted's or Highland Park or
whatever,
or,
you know, how do we approach that? Because obviously we can't just, you know, leave them hanging.
You know, we can't have people starving,
but we've got to be able to do it safely.
So my, what I'm leaning towards at this point is,
you know, giving them transportation
for food,
probably to stop and shop and using the early morning
at six to 7AM window.
>> Okay.
And actually, that might work out okay.
I talked with Ellie, and Ellie told me that
she would be happy to do you know, take them to the store if that's worth the plan.
But, also, she is willing to drive over to Ted's and pick up the food for them. Or I think I think what they're they
I think what the two people involved are going to do, they're gonna continue to call the store, get give them the list or send them the list on email.
And then they are going to the store will pack the groceries,
and then Ellie will drive up. That's what the we thought the plan was. And the boxes will bags will be put into the van,
and then she will deliver them to the two people.
Now if I I remember very well that there is one issue, and you will will recall the issue. So that might very well be that we'll just start taking the two of them to the store
just to see how that works out. That might be very good. I like that idea.
And Ellie is very willing and prepared
to do that.
So
you should probably make that decision at some point. Let me know because we're definitely prepared.
We're ready to go.
>> Understood.
Yeah. That decision will get made sometime this week. Not sure exactly. And I don't and, Eric, I don't want to start back the,
>> full bus of taking to stores yet.
I I I think two, that's great. I think that will work out really good because we can separate them.
>> Oh, no. We're not talking about taking two at the same time. We're talking about taking one at a time
>> on Tuesday. Fine too. Okay. Alright. Yeah.
Alright. That's fine.
I think, though,
senior day is Tuesday. So they would go on Tuesday to get the 10% discount.
But maybe we can alternate it. So one could go one Tuesday, one could go another.
Let's let's see how we can work that out.
>> Yeah. And the other thing is Ellie's gonna have to be willing to get up early to deliver them early because I think that's I'm going to call her. Eight window.
>> One of them is not an early riser, but perhaps she will.
>> Well, if it's the difference between that and starving to death, she'll probably get out. I
>> will, I will text you what I find out today.
>> Okay.
And,
Daryl,
how are we doing in terms of police response and
the needs of the community from your perspective?
>> It's been very busy lately. The month of May, we, town of Annover had over 200 calls for service.
So,
nothing that we can't handle.
Obviously, with the protests now starting,
it has even more ramped up, but,
we are we are well prepared. So there's, always somebody in town. If it's not me, it's definitely, you know, another patrol guy. So,
I worked Saturday evening.
It was it was extremely busy
within the Northeast Corridor here. So,
you know, things are starting to heat up as more people, start leaving their homes. But
rest assured, we're out there.
>> Excellent.
And anything you need from the town in terms of support services?
>> No. I know that, I haven't been in the office a lot lately, so,
you'll start seeing me around more often.
And,
but I'm fully equipped with the proper
PPE
and,
I don't, require anything at this time so I appreciate it though. Okay,
>> stay safe and if that changes let us know.
Most certainly will. Thank you. Okay. So last thing from the town's perspective.
The governor's obviously put out a
a really large number of executive orders and at one point or another I have read through all of them but being infinitely
familiar with all roughly 50 of them
is difficult.
So the two things I know is that they've relaxed the
maximum
group size to 10
individuals
but still recommending
that masks be worn and social distancing be in effect at
times for in general.
So what we have done at the town hall is we have essentially rotated employees through
so that in any given
office there will be a maximum of one employee working.
If you're going into somebody else's office you're expected to wear a mask
and the goal is to you know minimize direct contact between employees so when we do get one of them that tests positive for COVID it doesn't wipe out the whole office
or kill too many people off.
As
far as the
protocols
for reopening
the town hall, that's to a large extent a board of selectman decision.
However, when you really look at what it requires,
what we're required to do before we open up to the public,
it's fairly intensive
in terms of
disinfection protocols
as well as putting physical barriers in place.
So if we're going to do that,
it's going to take a bunch of reconstruction in the town hall and we're going to have to put up a bunch of plexiglass shielding
and we'll probably have to swap out a bunch of doors
to half doors so people can approach an office, but they can't actually enter it.
So
I'm actually hoping to just sit it out for another month or two
and not go through that construction phase and just basically wait it out. But it's going to depend in part on what the board of selectmen
choose to do because ultimately that's not not really all my decision or not even mostly my decision.
So that's
pretty much it.
This
is a
special meeting.
So there's limitations on what other things we can discuss.
But
I can certainly field any general questions from any of you if you have any questions about what the town's doing or town priorities or things of that nature
at this point.
>> Couple questions for you.
Sure. Are town employees being tested?
Nope.
Okay.
And the the library is saving all the receipts for all this COVID nineteen
equipment and, you know, plexiglass and gloves and all that sort of thing.
Hopefully that they'll be reimbursed either from what the feds of the state or from town somebody at the end
>> possibly
I mean you know we've been told that there will be reimbursement
for roughly 75%
of our expenses
but having sat through several of the FEMA,
the state FEMA briefings and other briefings on
all of this they haven't the state really has no idea what they're doing
In truth,
it's been an incredibly ineffective
organization
to deal with. So I don't even know who I'm applying to. I mean, I have set us up an account with FEMA.
So we are a,
you know, interested agency or whatever you call it.
But the state has said not to apply to FEMA at this point because there's so many different programs out there and they don't know which program should be used for which thing at this point.
So it's really kind of
you know
maddening
but
you know
that's the status.
So
I wish I had a better answer for you.
We will continue to save our receipts. Exactly.
And you said you had one more question?
About testing of the employees. Oh okay okay
>> yeah I mean we've submitted a list to the state
of all the employees that we have and what hours they work
because there's some rumor that they're going to start permitting
employees
you know have some kind of portal or methodology
for testing
municipal employees
but we haven't gotten anything back on that yet
in terms of what or even what that testing will be will it be antibody testing
will be at the standard COVID-nineteen
nasal swab
what they're talking about so
you know that's another thing I you
know I'm cc'd on all the emails from the emergency management
you know coordinator
but there's not been a lot of details
I know the fire department has made a decision to opt out of the testing.
Yeah
but that's all I know at this point.
If testing is available, ends up available to town employees,
I will encourage employees to get tested.
But I mean, I think that was primarily
get tested just prior to reopening to the public. So I don't think we would be there yet anyway.
Other questions?
Kurt, Daryl,
Kathy, do any of you have anything else?
No. I'm good.
>> I'm all set. Thank you. Okay. So what I would say is just be safe.
Notify me of what affects your individual departments.
If you have questions or concerns, you all have my phone number,
and email address. I will try to address them in a in a reasonably
proficient fashion.
That's all I have for me and unless anybody has anything else.
Okay, in that case I would entertain a motion to adjourn.
So moved.
Second.
>> Okay.
All those in favor say aye.
Aye.
Any opposed?
Any abstentions?
Motion carries four zero zero. Thank you all.
>> Eric, I have one question for you before we leave. Is the connectivity grant still